Guide to the Carlyle S. Baer Correspondence with Samuel X. Radbill
Yale University Arts Library
Carlyle S. Baer correspondence with Samuel X. Radbill
1936-1967
BKP 137
Yale University Arts Library
0.25
(1 box)
The collection contains just over 50 letters, typed and handwritten, between Carlyle S. Baer, secretary of the American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers, and Dr. Samuel X. Radbill, a bookplate collector.
Baer, Carlyle S. (Carlyle Solomon)
Radbill, Samuel X., 1901-1987
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by purchase, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains just over 50 letters, both typed and handwritten, between Carlyle S. Baer, secretary of the American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers, and Dr. Samuel X. Radbill, a pediatrician, medical historian, and collector of books and bookplates. Most letters are authored by Baer on Society letterhead, although the collection includes a few letters from Radbill as well. Subjects include Society business, such as yearbooks, membership dues, etc.; bookplate collecting and trading; Radbill's research and scholarship on medical ex-libris; and general bookplate news and trends.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Letters; Bookplates; Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1936-1967
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, November 25, 1936; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, December 2, 1936; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 10, 1939; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 17, 1940; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, April 2, 1940; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 30, 1941; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, November 18, 1947; 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes purchaser's receipt for membership dues.
  - Receipt for membership dues, November 22, 1947; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes receipt for membership dues.
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 23, 1948; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, August 5, 1948; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, August 21, 1948; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 25, 1949; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, June 20, 1949; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, July 10, 1949; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, November 19, 1949; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, January 21, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, March 4, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, April 22, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, April 29, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, May 4, 1950; 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, June 4, 1950; 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Includes purchaser's receipt for reprints.
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, June 9, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, November 25, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, December 2, 1950; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, January 14, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, January 20, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, May 6, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, May 25, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Carbon copy TLS to Mr. Baer from Dr. Radbill, June 27, 1951; 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - TLS to Dr. Radbill, June 30, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Carbon copy TLS to Mr. Baer from Dr. Radbill, July 10, 1951; 1 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ALS to Samuel X, July 21, 1951; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, January 6, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - TLS to Mr. Baer, April 7, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, April 13, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - TLS to Mr. Baer, April 17, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - TLS to Mr. Baer, May 28, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - ALS to Dr. Radbill, May 30, 1952; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - TLS to Carlisle [sic], June 2, 1952; 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - ALS to Radbill, January 1, 1953; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - ALS to Radbill, February 23, 1953; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - ALS to Radbill, June 26, 1953; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - ALS to Carlyle, June 28, 1955; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Letter also includes a draft of Baer's response.
  - ALS to Radbill, September 24, 1955; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - ALS to Radbill, July 28, 1957; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - TLS to Dr. Radbill, October 27, 1962; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - TLS to Radbill, November 17, 1962; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - TLS to Radbill, December 7, 1962; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - TLS to Dr. Radbill, January 13, 1967; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - TLS to Radbill, January 16, 1967; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - TLS to Dr. Radbill, January 31, 1967; 1 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - TLS to Dr. Radbill, March 6, 1967; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - TLS to Doctor Radbill, March 15, 1967; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 53)